# **Robert Dargavel Smith**

#### Machine Learning Engineer & Quantitative Analyst

Authorized to work in the UK and EU

in/attentioncoach github.com/teticio deej-ai.online

## Summary

I am both a highly technical Individual Contributor and Manager, with many years of experience of building and leading teams and deploying models in production. I am passionate about sharing knowledge and collaboration, and by nature I am very driven and extremely persistent.

# **Tech Stack**

Python - Hugging Face - PyTorch - Tensor Flow - Docker - Git - Helm - Kubernetes - Terraform - AWS (Lambda, EC2, SageMaker) - JavaScript - ReactJS - React Native - Selenium - Linux - C++ - C - Elasticsearch

## **Professional Experience**

#### Director Machine Learning Engineering, Clarity Al

London, UK 4/2022 - present

- Lead
  - Reporting to CTO, managing 10 people.
  - Lead hiring of 5 Data Scientists.
  - Leading all NLP projects (Information Extraction from PDFs, Controversies in news, Generative AI).
  - Created MLE team to bridge the gap with Engineering, focusing on tooling, implementation of best practices.
  - Gained trust of Engineering to manage cloud infrastructure thus increasing autonomy.
- Hands-on
  - SageMaker Studio for Teams. Developed IaC and tooling to replace existing ML platform, leading to \$500K p.a. savings.
  - GitLab quality. Implemented pragmatic rules and automated monitoring to improve code quality.
  - Brand2Company. Developed methods to map brand names to company IDs.
  - Ethical web-scraping. Employed techniques to obtain data for POCs.
  - Llama (LoRA). Fine-tuned LLMs on specialized tasks.
  - Policy detection. Improved HITL process and fine-tuning of BERT models, trained to detect compliance with a policy.
  - OpenAl Proxy. Deployed API gateway for fine-grained monitoring / control of OpenAl usage by project.

Head of Data Science, IHS Markit (now roughly one third of S&P Global) London, UK 4/2020 - 4/2022

- Reported directly into Executive Vice President group CTO of IHS Markit (16,000 employees).
- Managed Centre of Excellence of 20 Data Scientists based in London, Gdansk and Bangalore.
- Collaborated with all business verticals (Financial Services, Automotive, Energy, Maritime & Trade).

#### Managing Director, Santander Group

**Madrid, Spain** 1/2001 - 3/2020

- Several roles including Global Head of Quantitative Analysis and Head of CVA Desk.
- Built and led team of over 20 people from more than 10 nationalities based in Madrid, London & New York.
- Started CVA Desk, managing change across all affected areas & locations and transforming regulatory requirement into opportunity.
- Frequent speaker at industry conferences in Europe, USA & Asia.

#### Quantitative Analyst, ABN Amro

**London, UK** 1995 - 1/2021

• Developed models in C for hedging and valuing equity derivatives and convertible bonds.

#### Software Engineer, Harlequin (now Global Graphics)

Cambridge, UK 1993 - 1995

• Developed device drivers for commercial printing presses.

## **Projects**

- Audio diffusion. Music generation, included in Hugging Face's Diffusers package.
- Deej-Al. Playlist generation with a Deep Convolutional Neural Network trained on audio samples.
- Lambda scraper. AWS Lambda functions as a proxy pool for web scraping.
- LALAL.AI. Collaboration with a startup specializing in stemming audios with ML.

## **Academic Experience**

Professor, MBIT School Madrid, Spain 2020

Advanced Machine Learning Expert Programme, specializing in Deep Neural Networks and NLP.

Professor, Universidad de Alcalá Madrid, Spain 2013 - 2020

Masters of Artificial Intelligence and Masters of Quantitative Finance.

### **Publications**

Landmarks in XVA: From Counterparty Risk to Funding Costs and Capital, Risk Books

Chapter on "Managing XVA in the Ring Fenced Bank".

An Almost Exact Simulation Method for the Heston Model, Journal of Computational Finance 2007

#### **Education**

Advanced Machine Learning Expert Programme, MBIT School Ma

Madrid, Spain 2019

Awarded maximum grade and was invited to be a Professor in subsequent editions of the course.

BA First Class Honors in Mathematics Pembroke College, University of Oxford

Oxford, UK 1990-1993

Awarded Pembroke College prize for Mathematics.

#### Fun facts

- Actor in several amateur theatre productions (Carlton Theatre Group, Honda Teatro).
- Certified Mindfulness (MBCT) Instructor.
- Marathon runner (PB 2:47 New York City, 2013).
- Ironman Finisher (Florianopolis, Brazil, 2011).
- DJ (club, radio, produced 12" single featured on Gilles Peterson compilation).
- Bronze medalist in World Rowing Junior Championships (coxed four, 1990).

# Natural Languages

• **English** [Native]

• Spanish [Bilingual]